Guide to the William Upcott, Original Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
"Original letters collected by William Upcott of the London Institution Dukes and Marquesses. First series."
1824-1824
OSBORN D194
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.16
(1 volume)
Autograph MSS. Letters mounted in an album.
Upcott, William, 1779-1845
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn d194. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Autographs -- Great Britain; Nobility -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Upcott, William, 1779-1845
- Osborn d194
  - ABERCORN, ANNA JANE HAMILTON, MARCHIONESS OF, 1763-1827
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, n.d. (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      n.p.
      1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Concerns a bill.
      d 194/69
  - ABERCORN, ANNA JANE HAMILTON, MARCHIONESS OF, 1763-1827
    - ALS to [Edward?] Evans (1789-1835), n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Requests the price of the "Travels
      of India" by William Hodges, R.A.
      (1744-1797).
      d 194/70
  - ARGYLL, GEORGE WILLIAM CAMPBELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1768-1839
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Hanley, 1816 Sep 8 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Desires five proofs of the portrait
      print of Lord Frederick Campbell
      (1782-1846).
      d 194/1
  - ATHOLL, MARGERY (FORBES) MURRAY, DUCHESS OF, D. 1842
    - AL (in third person) to an unnamed recipient, 1806 Dec 23 (Box 1)
      Dunkeld
      1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Order for a dress and fabric.
      d 194/2
  - BATH, THOMAS THYNNE, MARQUESS OF, 1765-1837
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1808 Feb 15 (Box 1)
      Grovesnor Square
      Accepts the Vice Presidency of the
      Vaccine Institution.
      d 194/72
  - BEAUFORT, CHARLOTTE SOPHIA SOMERSET, DUCHESS OF, 1771-1854
    - AL (in third person) to Dr. Wingfield, [no yr.] Oct 29 (Box 1)
      Badminton
      1 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Would like more attention from him.
      d 194/3
  - BEAUFORT, CHARLOTTE SOPHIA SOMERSET, DUCHESS OF, 1771-1854
    - AL (in third person) to Henry Colburn (d. 1855), 1816 Dec (Box 1)
      Whichwood Park
      1 p.; 17 x 12 cm.
      Places book orders.
      d 194/4
  - BEDFORD, GEORGIANA ELIZABETH RUSSELL, DUCHESS OF, D. 1801
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Edwards, [no yr.] Oct 20 (Box 1)
      Stratton Park
      Places an order.
      d 194/7
  - BEDFORD, GEORGIANA ELIZABETH RUSSELL, DUCHESS OF, D. 1801
    - AL to Mrs. Plowman, draper, 1807 Dec 28 (Box 1)
      Woburn Abbey
      1 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
      Orders fabric.
      d 194/11
  - BEDFORD, JOHN RUSSELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1766-1839
    - AL (in third person) to Boydell and Co., 1795 Jun 30 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Orders the subscription prints of the
      Shakespeare Gallery by John Boydell
      (1719-1804).
      d 194/6
  - BEDFORD, JOHN RUSSELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1766-1839
    - LS to an unnamed recipient, 1810 Apr 2 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Thanks him for his shipment of
      "Oriental Scenery" and asks for the
      account balance.
      d 194/8
  - BEDFORD, JOHN RUSSELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1766-1839
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1812 Mar 29 (Box 1)
      Thanks for the notification of a
      change of address.
      d 194/9
  - BEDFORD, JOHN RUSSELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1766-1839
    - ALS to Mr. Jeffrey, 1817 Aug 2 (Box 1)
      London
      2 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Asks for books to be sent to Woburn
      Abbey.
      d 194/10
  - BOLTON, HARRY PAULET, 6TH DUKE OF, 1719-1794
    - AL to an unnamed recipient, 1773 Dec 11 (Box 1)
      Hackwood
      1 p.; 25 x 19 cm.
      Places an order for books.
      d 194/12
  - BUCCLEUCH, HARRIET CATHERINE SCOTT, DUCHESS OF, 1773-1814
    - AL to [Edward?] Evans (1789-1835), n.d. (Box 1)
      Richmond
      d 194/14
  - CORNWALLIS, LOUISA CORNWALLIS, MARCHIONESS, 1776-1850
    - AL to John Walker (1759-1830), 1814 Jan 8 (Box 1)
      Culford
      1 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Requests that the vaccine virus be
      sent for a large family surrounded by
      smallpox.
      d 194/75
  - DONEGALL, ANNA (MAY) CHICHESTER, MARCHIONESS OF, D. 1849
    - AL (in third person) to Henry Colburn (d. 1855), 1808 Apr 18 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Orders books.
      d 194/80
  - DONEGALL, ARTHUR CHICHESTER, MARQUIS OF, 1739-1799
    - AL to the [Lord Mayor of London?], 1797 Oct 5 (Box 1)
      St. James Square
      Makes an appointment.
      d 194/79
  - DORSET, JOHN FREDERICK SACKVILLE, 3RD DUKE OF, 1745-1799
    - AL to the Hon. Mrs. Percy, 1780 Oct 14 (Box 1)
      Knole
      Asks permission for the painter
      Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810) to copy
      the drawing of the portrait of
      "Sacharissa" by Sir Anthony Van Dyke
      (1599-1641) in her collection.
      d 194/21
  - DORSET, JOHN FREDERICK SACKVILLE, 3RD DUKE OF, 1745-1799
    - AL to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), 1789 Sep 8 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      Makes an appointment with the
      painter.
      d 194/22
  - EXETER, CECIL BROWNLOW, 9TH EARL OF, 1725-1793
    - 2 ALS to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), 1773 (Box 1)
      1773 Oct 8 and Dec 19
      About two paintings, one presumably
      a portrait, and their delivery.
      d 194/85-6
  - EXETER, CECIL BROWNLOW, 9TH EARL OF, 1725-1793
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), n.d. (Box 1)
      [London]
      Lord Exeter's concerns over the fate
      over a painting by Titian which he
      fears may go to America.
      d 194/87
  - EXETER, ELIZABETH ANNE CECIL, MARCHIONESS OF, 1757-1837
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), 1783 May 19 (Box 1)
      Makes an appointment to sit for him.
      d 194/30
  - EXETER, ELIZABETH ANNE CECIL, MARCHIONESS OF, 1757-1837
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), [1783] (Box 1)
      Apologizes for having forgotten an
      appointment.
      d 194/31
  - EXETER, ELIZABETH ANNE CECIL, MARCHIONESS OF, 1757-1837
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Dulau, n.d. (Box 1)
      d 194/89
  - EXETER, HENRY CECIL, MARQUIS OF, 1754-1804
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1801 Oct 28 (Box 1)
      [Burghley]
      Sends along a roll of prints and
      four books which he suspects may
      belong to the recipient.
      d 194/88
  - GRAFTON, MARY CAROLINE FITZROY, DUCHESS OF, 1795-1873
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Abel, 1815 Sep 14 (Box 1)
      Stony Stratford
      Informs him of her imminent
      departure and her need to suspend her
      subscription.
      d 194/29
  - HAMILTON, ALEXANDER HAMILTON, 10TH DUKE OF, 1767-1852
    - AL to Mr. Meyer, 1805 Apr 3 (Box 1)
      Concerns the lettering on two books.
      d 194/82
  - HAMILTON, SUSAN EUPHEMIA HAMILTON, DUCHESS OF, 1786-1859
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Clarke, 1815 Jan 19 (Box 1)
      Hamilton Palace
      1 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Concerns a draft on Hoare and Co.
      d 194/83
  - HAMILTON, SUSAN EUPHEMIA HAMILTON, DUCHESS OF, 1786-1859
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Clarke, [no yr.] Feb 19 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
      Requests books in French.
      d 194/84
  - HERTFORD, FRANCIS SEYMOUR-CONWAY, MARQUIS OF, 1718-1794
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, [1780] Apr 21 (Box 1)
      Assures the recipient of his good
      will and faith.
      d 194/89x
  - LEEDS, GEORGE WILLIAM FREDERICK OSBORNE, DUKE OF, 1775-1838
    - ALS to Boydell and Co., 1807 Aug 22 (Box 1)
      Hornby Castle
      Encloses a receipt of a draft.
      d 194/32
  - MANCHESTER, WILLIAM MONTAGU, 5TH DUKE OF, 1768-1843
    - AL (in third person) to Josiah Boydell (1752-1817), [no yr.] Dec 26 (Box 1)
      Subscribes for prints from the
      drawings of Giovanni Battista
      Cipriani (1727-1785).
      d 194/33
  - MARLBOROUGH, CAROLINE SPENCER, DUCHESS OF, 1743-1811
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), [1788 or later?] (Box 1)
      Marlborough House
      2 p.; 18 x 14 cm.
      Sends a portrait drawing by Thomas
      Gainsborough (1727-1788) of her
      husband, George Spencer, 4th duke of
      Marlborough (1739-1817), and asks
      that Humphrey complete, and correct,
      the painted portrait from the
      drawing (presumably due to
      Gainsborough's death).
      d 194/35
  - MARLBOROUGH, GEORGE SPENCER-CHURCHILL, DUKE OF, 1766-1840
    - ALS to [Edward?] Evans, n.d. (Box 1)
      White Knights, Reading
      Requests that he attend the sale of
      John Sheldon's library on his behalf.
      d 194/36
  - MARLBOROUGH, GEORGE SPENCER-CHURCHILL, DUKE OF, 1766-1840
    - ALS to Mr. Dulau, 1800 Dec 26 (Box 1)
      Requests that books be sent.
      d 194/37
  - MARLBOROUGH, GEORGE SPENCER-CHURCHILL, DUKE OF, 1766-1840
    - ALS to Mr. Hayes, bookbinder, 1814 Sep 12 (Box 1)
      A letter sending instructions.
      d 194/38
  - MONTROSE, JAMES GRAHAM, 3RD DUKE OF, 1755-1836
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), 1805 Apr 7 (Box 1)
      Declines a portrait.
      d 194/39
  - NORTHUMBERLAND, HUGH PERCY, 2ND DUKE OF, 1742-1817
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Budd, 1805 Apr 11 (Box 1)
      Newcastle
      Orders "Cobbett's Weekly Political
      Register" run by William Cobbett
      (1763-1835).
      d 194/45
  - PETTY, LORD WILLIAM
    - AL (in third person) to B. Penn, 1806 Apr 12 (Box 1)
      Obliged for a letter.
      d 194/92
  - PORTLAND, MARGARET CAVENDISH BENTINCK, DUCHESS OF, 1715-1785
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), 1784 Nov 24 (Box 1)
      Bulstrode
      Offers to buy the two pictures and
      the drawings he had sent.
      d 194/50
  - PORTLAND, WILLIAM HENRY BENTINCK, DUKE OF, 1738-1809
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 13 x 19 cm.
      On the delivery of a picture.
      d 194/48
  - PORTLAND, WILLIAM HENRY BENTINCK, DUKE OF, 1768-1854
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1808 Jan 23 (Box 1)
      Declines the honor of being a Vice
      President of the Vaccine Institution.
      d 194/51
  - PORTLAND, WILLIAM HENRY BENTINCK, DUKE OF, 1768-1854
    - ALS to Sir Benjamin Thompson, Count Rumford (1753-1814), 1810 Jun 16 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      On land he owns at Bulstrode.
      d 194/52
  - RICHMOND, CHARLES LENNOX, 3RD DUKE OF, 1735-1806
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), n.d. (Box 1)
      Asks Humphrey to persuade George
      Romney (1734-1802) to paint "Mr.
      Bentinck" [?William Henry Cavendish
      Bentinck, 3rd Duke of Portland
      (1738-1809)].
      d 194/55
  - RICHMOND, CHARLES LENNOX, 3RD DUKE OF, 1735-1806
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), [no yr.] Jun 5 (Box 1)
      Whitehall
      2 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Wishes Henry Singleton (1766-1839)
      would overcome his fears and begin
      the copy of a painting by Sir
      Anthony Van Dyke (1599-1641)
      requested by the Duke.
      d 194/56
  - RICHMOND, CHARLOTTE (GORDON) LENNOX, DUCHESS OF, 1768-1842
    - AL (in third person) to Robert Plowman and Co., furnishers, [1813] Oct 17 (Box 1)
      Goodwood
      Requests information about
      furniture; a draft reply by "R.P.
      and Co." is appended.
      d 194/57
  - RUTLAND, ELIZABETH (HOWARD) MANNERS, DUCHESS OF, 1780-1825
    - AL (in third person) to Kent and Sons, firm, 1807 Nov 25 (Box 1)
      Belvoir Castle
      Seeks to buy a Persian carpet she
      saw while in London.
      d 194/59
  - ST. ALBANS, MARIA JANETTA BEAUCLERK, DUCHESS OF, D. 1822
    - ALS to Henry Colburn (d. 1855) (Box 1)
      Encloses a work (lacking) and asks
      that it be returned as soon as it is
      published.
      d 194/62
  - SALISBURY, JAMES CECIL, 1ST MARQUIS OF, 1748-1823
    - AL (in third person) to Henry Colburn (d. 1855), 1815 Oct 16 (Box 1)
      Aldbro
      1 p.; 26 x 19 cm.
      Orders "Loisirs de Bonaparte".
      d 194/96
  - SALISBURY, JAMES CECIL, 1ST MARQUIS OF, 1748-1823
    - AL (in third person) to Robarts and Co., firm, 1808 Oct 13 (Box 1)
      Order for silk.
      d 194/97
  - SOMERSET, CHARLOTTE (HAMILTON) SEYMOUR, DUCHESS OF, 1772-1827
    - AL (in third person) to John Foster, n.d. (Box 1)
      Order for furniture.
      d 194/63
  - SOMERSET, CHARLOTTE (HAMILTON) SEYMOUR, DUCHESS OF, 1772-1827
    - AL (in third person) to Mr. Dulau, 1806 Sep 18 (Box 1)
      Bradley
      Order for books.
      d 194/64
  - TEMPLE, CHANDOS
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1802 Sep 12 (Box 1)
      Avington
      Requests the newly published
      "Travels in Upper and Lower Egypt"
      by Vivant Denon.
      d 194/74
  - THOMOND, MARY (PALMER) O'BRIEN, MARCHIONESS OF, 1750-1820
    - AL (in third person) to William Collom, 1816 Aug 25 (Box 1)
      Baylis
      Refuses to consent to publication of
      a "Jeu d'Esprit" of Sir Joshua
      Reynolds (1723-1792).
      d 194/100
  - WHITWORTH, ARABELLA DIANA WHITWORTH, COUNTESS, 1769-1825
    - AL (in third person) to Ozias Humphrey (1742-1810), 1791 Aug 15 (Box 1)
      Admires an engraving after a
      portrait by Sir Joshua Reynolds
      (1723-1792).
      d 194/24
  - WHITWORTH, ARABELLA DIANA WHITWORTH, COUNTESS, 1769-1825
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1810 Jul 17 (Box 1)
      Buckhurst
      Sends some miniatures.
      d 194/25